I’m working a lot with motion and animation,
أعمل مع الكثير من الحركة والرسوم المتحركة
and also I'm an old DJ and a musician.
وأنا أيضاً لاعب موسيقى قديم وموسيقار.
So, music videos are something that I always found interesting,
اذاً فموسيقى الفيديو هي شئ أجده دائماً مثير،
but they always seem to be so reactive.
لكنه دائماً يبدو كرد فعل.
So I was thinking, can you remove us as creators
لذا كنت أفكر، هل يمكن إزالتنا نحن كمبتدعين
and try to make the music be the voice
ونحاول أن نجعل الموسيقى هي الصوت
and have the animation following it?
ونجعل الرسوم المتحركة تتبعها.
So with two designers, Tolga and Christina, at my office, we took a track --
لذا مع مصممين، كريستينا وتولقا، في مكتبي، أخذنا مقطع موسيقي--
many of you probably know it. It’s about 25 years old,
من المرجح أن كثيرين منكم يعرفونه، حول 25 سنة،
and it's David Byrne and Brian Eno --
وهي لديفيد برين وبرين إينو--
and we did this little animation.
وصنعنا هذه الرسوم المتحركة البسيطة.
And I think that it's maybe interesting, also,
وأعتقد أن هذا ربما مثير أيضاً
that it deals with two problematic issues,
لأنها تتعامل مع قضيتين إشكاليتين،
which are rising waters and religion.
وهي إرتفاع المياه والدين.
Song: Before God destroyed the people on the Earth,
قبل أن يهلك الإله الناس على الأرض،
he warned Noah to build an Ark.
أمر نوح أن يبني السفينة.
And after Noah built his Ark,
وبعد أن بنى نوح السفينة،
I believe he told Noah to warn the people
أعتقد أنه أخبر نوح بتحذير الناس
that they must change all their wicked ways
من أنهم يجب أن يتركوا كل الطرق الشريرة
before he come upon them and destroy them.
قبل أن يأتي عليهم ويهلكهم.
And when Noah had done built his Ark,
وعندما أنتهى نوح من بناء السفينة،
I understand that somebody began to rend a song.
أفهم أن شخص ما بدأ بتقطيع أغنية.
And the song began to move on I understand like this.
وبدأت الأغنية في الإنتشار أنا افهمها هكذا.
And when Noah had done built his Ark ...
وعندما أنتهى نوح من بناء السفينة...
Move on ... In fact ... Concern ...
تحرك...
So they get tired, has come dark and rain; they get weary and tired.
اذاً فقد انهكوا، جاء الظلام والمطر. أحسوا بالضجر والملل.
And then he went and knocked an old lady house.
وبعد ذلك ذهب وطرق باب منزل سيدة عجوز.
And old lady ran to the door and say, "Who is it?"
وهرعت السيدة العجوز الى الباب قائلة: " من أنت؟"
Jack say, "Me, Mama-san, could we spend the night here?
قالت والدة جاكسون لي: " هل يمكننا قضاء الليلة هنا؟"
Because we’re far from home, we’re very tired."
" لأننا بعيدون من بيتنا، نحن متعبون جداً"
And the old lady said, "Oh yes, come on in."
وردت السيدة العجوز: "أوه نعم، تفضلوا بالدخول."
It was come dark and rain, will make you weary and tired.
لقد حلّ الظلام وجاء المطر، سيصيبك بالضجر والملل.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)